mazda.ca 2018-09-04

# Privacy Policy | Mazda Canada

### MAZDA'S PRIVACY POLICY

Mazda Canada Inc. is the distributor of Mazda vehicles in Canada (referred to hereafter as Mazda). Mazda is a subsidiary of Mazda Motor Corporation in Hiroshima, Japan and was established in 1968. Our automotive products are distributed in Canada through a network of dealers authorized by Mazda, which are independently owned and operated businesses, which may have their own privacy policies and procedures. You should contact your Mazda dealer for information about their privacy practices.

At Mazda we take individual privacy very seriously. We are strongly committed to providing a transparent and coordinated approach to managing interactions with our customers. This Privacy Policy complies with the Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act and applicable provincial privacy laws. It is also a reflection of our guiding principle: that at Mazda, people come first. At Mazda we focus on our customers, creating relationships inspired by mutual respect and trust.

This Mazda Privacy Policy covers all modes of interaction between Mazda and our customers, including in-person, over the telephone and over the Internet, directly and indirectly, when we collect personal information about individuals from our dealers.

By choosing to submit personal information to Mazda, you signify your consent to all of the terms of this "Privacy Policy". If you do not agree with any terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not submit any personal information to Mazda.

###### 1\. What personal information does Mazda collect?

Personal information is information about an identifiable individual. Personal information consisting of the name, title or business address or business telephone number of an employee is not considered personal information. Mazda collects personal information in a number of ways and through a number of different media. Typically, Mazda will collect personal information directly from an individual, or indirectly through a Mazda dealer or affiliated Mazda Company. Mazda may collect and use personal information in one, or more, of the following circumstances:

  * When a dealer discloses information to Mazda about a potential customer, including that individual's name, address and contact details, for the purpose of ongoing communications relating to the potential purchase or lease of a Mazda product;
  * At or following a test-drive when a dealer may disclose information from the individual's Driver's Licence to Mazda confirming the customer has a valid driver's licence for insurance-related purposes;
  * Once a customer purchases a new Mazda vehicle, when the dealer discloses information to Mazda, including the customer's name, address, contact and licence details, for warranty administration and ongoing customer communications and vehicle service-related purposes;
  * Once a customer arranges financing for a new vehicle through The Bank of Nova Scotia or TD Auto Finance, the dealer discloses information to Mazda about the lease vehicle and financing information (which may constitute personal financial information if linked with other personal information) for marketing and product development purposes;
  * Through surveys, research and customer-initiated contact, to enable Mazda to constantly improve the quality of our product and service offerings;
  * In the course of making available offers, incentives, marketing programs or promotional materials when Mazda may collect certain customer profile information to learn more about our existing and potential customers' preferences to better tailor our products and services to their ever-changing needs;
  * On contest entry forms, so that Mazda can confirm contest winners' identities and obtain their contact information to communicate with them to administer the contest;
  * When individuals provide Mazda with name and contact information by participating in "join our mailing list" initiatives;
  * When contacting us for further information;
  * When contacting us for test-drive registration;
  * When registering for on-line services;
  * For program verification purposes;
  * By way of Mazda websites, where individuals may be requested to provide name, address and contact information to enable us to communicate with them;
  * When an individual services their vehicle at a dealer, when this service information is disclosed to Mazda for marketing purposes; and
  * Whenever you otherwise provide us with personal information.

Personal information collected by Mazda typically consists of basic contact information: name, title, home address, e-mail address, and telephone and fax numbers. We may also collect demographic information such as a customer's gender; age and occupation, to better understand our customers and service their needs and for marketing purposes. Visitors to the Mazda web site are able to send e-mails to third parties from our web site. These messages may contain the user's full name, screen name and e-mail address, as well as additional personal information voluntarily included in the message.

Visitors to Mazda's website are not required to register or provide personal information to gain access. However, as Mazda's website evolves and becomes more interactive, and as the website becomes a repository for increasingly personalized customer information, Mazda may require visitors to register and provide user identification or authentication information. Such information will be required in order to secure and prevent unauthorized access to or theft of this information and for no other purposes.

Sensitive personal information can include a number of types of information relating to an individual's race or ethnic origin; political opinions; religious or other similar beliefs; trade union membership; physical or mental health; sexual orientation or criminal record. We do not require individuals to provide, such sensitive personal information, except under our Mobility Program. In the case of the Mobility Program, sensitive information relating to an individual's physical infirmary may be collected by Mazda or by a Mazda dealer from that customer and provided to Mazda during the course of the vehicle sale or lease to confirm the customer qualifies for purchase and installation assistance of adaptive driving aids or mobility assistance equipment. We do not otherwise solicit sensitive personal information and recommend that you do not provide such sensitive information. If you voluntarily provide sensitive personal information for any reason, you understand and agree that by doing so you have provided your express consent to Mazda to use that information in the manner described in this Privacy Policy, or for the purpose(s) described to the individual at the time the information was provided.

Service data recorders (SDR) in your vehicle are capable of collecting and storing diagnostic information about your vehicle, which may constitute personal information. This may include information about the performance or status of various systems and modules in the vehicle, such as engine, throttle, steering or brake systems. Your Mazda dealer may access and collect this vehicle diagnostic information through a direct connection to your vehicle during the servicing process. The only circumstance in which this information may be disclosed to Mazda or Mazda Motor Corporation is in connection with providing service in relation to your vehicle, except as otherwise required by law. This data will enable Mazda Motor Corporation to provide its markets (distributors/dealers) with relevant information according to the data collected to support diagnosis and repair work at dealers.

Other modules in your vehicle, including event data recorders (EDR), are capable of collecting and storing data during a collision or near collision. The modules may record information about both the vehicle and the occupants, potentially including information such as:

  * how various systems in your vehicle were operating;
  * whether or not the driver and passenger seatbelts were buckled;
  * how far if at all the driver was depressing the accelerator and or the brake pedal;
  * how fast the vehicle was travelling; and
  * where the driver was positioning the steering wheel.

Special equipment must be directly connected to the recording modules to access EDR information. Mazda does not access, collect, use or disclose EDR information without your consent, unless required under court order or elsewhere otherwise required by law.

###### 2\. How is personal information used?

Mazda may collect and use personal information in the circumstances described in paragraph 1 above. Information collected by Mazda is used only for the purpose identified at the time of its collection, as described in this policy, or for other purposes which are disclosed to you and to which you consent.

We may also use your personal information to investigate security breaches or cooperate with government authorities pursuant to a legal matter.

Personal information we collect may also be combined with information you have provided to Mazda through other sources such as over the telephone.

In the case of personal contact information provided in conjunction with "join our mailing list initiatives" or other marketing initiatives, you can unsubscribe to any Mazda subscriptions by contacting the Mazda Privacy Officer by clicking on [privacy@mazda.ca](mailto:privacy@mazda.ca "Privacy Email") or by calling 1-866-864-3536 or by writing to us at: Privacy Office, 55 Vogell Road, Richmond Hill ON, L4B 3K5.

###### 3\. How is personal information disclosed?

From time to time Mazda may engage unaffiliated third parties and their affiliates, agents and subcontractors ("Service Providers") to perform certain technological or administrative services for us. For example, a Service Provider may be asked to administer a contest or distribute email. We also may use a Service Provider to host and administer one or more of our Sites, process and store data, and fulfill similar technology-related functions on our behalf. In these circumstances, the personal information that the Service Provider receives is limited to only the personal information held by us that they need in order to render their service to us. The companies that are provided with the personal information are first required to sign an agreement that obligates them to keep the information confidential and secure and prohibits them from using it for unauthorized purposes.

We reserve the right to transfer any personal information we have about you in the event that we merge with or are acquired by a third party. We may also disclose your personal information to third parties if we have reason to believe that disclosing such information is necessary to: (i) conduct investigations of possible breaches of law; (ii) identify, contact, or bring legal action against someone who may be violating an agreement they have with us; or (iii) to protect our rights, safety or property. Lastly, we may disclose your personal information for any other purpose to which you consent.

###### 4\. How Mazda collects information through automatic means?

When you visit a Mazda-owned website, we may collect information that is automatically sent to us by your web browser or your internet service provider. This information may include your domain name, and your numerical IP address. We may also collect other general information (such as the type of browser you use, which pages on our website you view, and the files you request). We use this information to better understand how visitors use our websites, and to improve our websites to better meet your needs. The amount of information that is sent by your web browser depends on the browser and settings you use. Please refer to the instructions provided by your browser if you want to learn more about what information it sends to websites you visit, or how you may change or restrict this.

To enhance your experience on our websites, we may use a feature on your Internet browser called a "cookie" and/or other similar devices such as web beacons. Cookies are small files that your web browser places on your computer's hard drive. They are used for a variety of reasons, such as tracking click streams, and for load balancing. Information tracked through these mechanisms may include, but is not limited to: (i) your IP address; (ii) the type of web browser and operating system being used; and (iii) the pages of the websites a user visits. By using cookies, we can deliver faster service, consistent, updated results, and a better experience on our websites. Most browsers give you the option to reject cookies. However, setting your browser to reject cookies generally hinders the browser's performance and will adversely affect your experience while using our websites.

###### 5\. How long does Mazda retain your personal information?

Consistent with Canadian privacy law, Mazda retains your personal information only as long as necessary to fulfill the stated purpose(s) for its collection and use. Customer personal information collected for vehicle warranty administration is retained for ten years. Mazda reserves the rights to otherwise retain your personal information as may be required or permitted by law.

###### 6\. Accessing and updating your personal information?

You have the right to access, verify and correct your personal information collected by Mazda. To help us keep your personal information current, contact the Mazda Privacy Officer at [privacy@mazda.ca](mailto:privacy@mazda.ca "Privacy Email") or call us at 1-866-864-3536. When requested, Mazda will suppress identifying information from current operational systems for the purpose of mailings or other communications except in the case of recalls or other similar events.

When you ask to access your personal information, Mazda will use reasonable efforts to comply with your request; however, in some cases we may not be able to allow you to access certain personal information in certain circumstances, for example if it contains personal information of other persons, or for legal reasons. In such cases, we will provide you with a reasonable explanation of why it is not possible to grant access to your personal information.

To the extent permitted by law, Mazda assumes no responsibility for verifying the ongoing accuracy of personal information. Once advised that personal information is inaccurate, Mazda will seek to amend the information and correct it with information provided by the customer.

###### 7\. How is my information secured?

Mazda treats your information as private, confidential information and we strive to protect that information, both on-line and off-line, at all times. Mazda has implemented generally accepted physical, technological and operational security systems to help protect personally identifiable information from loss, theft, misuse, alteration or destruction. All Mazda employees, agents and authorized dealers are instructed about this Privacy Policy and are required to adhere to our security policy. Only personnel authorized by Mazda have access to personal information and these individuals are contractually required to preserve the confidentiality of this information. Personal information we collect is maintained in Irvine, California.

Although we have taken reasonable and prudent measures to protect our websites, computer systems and any personal information that it has collected from unauthorized use, access, disclosure, misuse, alteration or destruction, no security measures can provide absolute protection. As a result, while we are committed to protecting your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you provide to us.

Some or all of the personal information we collect may be stored or processed on servers located outside your jurisdiction of residence, including in the United States, whose data protection laws may differ from the jurisdiction in which you live. As a result, this information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in those jurisdictions according to laws in those jurisdictions. Subject to applicable laws in such other jurisdictions, we will use reasonable efforts to ensure that appropriate protections are in place to require the data processor in that country to maintain protections on the personal information that are equivalent to those that apply in Canada.

###### 8\. Changes to the Mazda Privacy Policy

Mazda reserves the right to modify or amend this Privacy Policy at any time and for any reason and as required by law. If Mazda updates this Privacy Policy, the new Privacy Policy will be posted at www.mazda.ca five days prior to the changes taking effect. We encourage individuals to check our homepage periodically for any updates to this policy. Your continued access to and/or use of a Mazda website, continued business with Mazda, or continued submission of personal information to Mazda, after any such changes, constitutes your acceptance of, and agreement to be legally bound by, this Privacy Policy, as revised. This Privacy Policy is effective July 1, 2014. You may determine when this policy was last updated by referring to the modification date at the bottom of the policy.

Canada's new anti-spam legislation (CASL) became effective July 1, 2014 and among other things will regulate the sending of commercial electronic messages (CEMs) by organizations such as Mazda. Mazda established an internal CASL Compliance Team to ensure Mazda is compliant with CASL. Mazda's approach to the issue of consent is to rely on implied consent for its existing and new customers based on its existing business relationship with its customers which is defined by the warranty coverage agreement. Implied consent applies for the length of the longest unlimited mileage warranty plus an additional two years.

###### 9\. Contact us

If you have any questions regarding this privacy policy, or the collection, use or disclosure of personal information by Mazda Canada Inc. you may contact the Mazda Privacy Officer by clicking on [privacy@mazda.ca ](mailto:privacy@mazda.ca "Privacy Email")or by calling 1-866-864-3536 or by writing to us at: Privacy Office, 55 Vogell Road, Richmond Hill ON, L4B 3K5.
